[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c056", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Israel?", "answer": "Hoopoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d0", "question": "What is the title of the bugle tune sounded as the introduction to a horse race?", "answer": "First Call", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc36", "question": "What basketball superstar is nicknamed \"His Airness\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69e7e20565ad31a57c784", "question": "During World War II, who was Norway's leader and chief Nazi collaborator?", "answer": "Vidkun Quisling", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0e", "question": "What position did Babe Ruth play when he first joined the Boston Red Sox in 1914?", "answer": "Pitcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec88acec223966ae8f8821", "question": "LCS is the acronym for a professional eSports league centered around which game?", "answer": "League of Legends", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc6536de0eb824d4052f7", "question": "What is the official state fruit of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523e38736d4be723796b4c", "question": "Which region of Canada would you find Canada\u2019s Technology Triangle?", "answer": "Waterloo Region", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6bd", "question": "On a standard color wheel, what color is opposite blue?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b636", "question": "Which salad dressing was named after a play?", "answer": "Green Goddess", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfb", "question": "How many enemy planes must a pilot shoot down to be called an ace?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0ae5ee662d71a53650fb9", "question": "A poorly supported yet persistent rumour has it that Denmark\u2019s King Christian VIII, not a shoemaker, was whose father?", "answer": "Hans Christian Andersen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb28a4c9bff04efae6d752", "question": "What massively successful novel did Mario Puzo publish in 1969?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6aa9220565ad31a57c81b", "question": "What was Hoover Dam's original name?", "answer": "Boulder Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339429", "question": "Who is \"The Jerk\"?", "answer": "Steve Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c9", "question": "What part of New York was called \"broken land\" by the Dutch?", "answer": "Brooklyn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339daa", "question": "What skateboarding actor-to-be plays the main character in Sonic Youth's music video for \"100%\"?", "answer": "Jason Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008b7acf842fa4c4ba9699", "question": "What is a funambulist?", "answer": "Tightrope walker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd4", "question": "Baklava is usually made using what kind of paper-thin dough?", "answer": "Filo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600781e8bd51d85e222ab650", "question": "Which of Picasso's paintings was considered immoral when it was first exhibited in 1916?", "answer": "Les Demoiselles d'Avignon\u00a0(The Young Ladies of Avignon), a depiction of 5 Barcelona prostitutes, was deemed immoral by the public.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc0e5ec223966ae8f8861", "question": "The U.S. Hockey team upset which team during the 1980 \"Miracle on Ice\"?", "answer": "USSR", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c6cb877e98cb977789c0", "question": "The Great Pyramid of Cholula is located in what country?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7ce67877e98cb97778a41", "question": "What is the oldest major city in the Philippines?", "answer": "Cebu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600784b0bd51d85e222ab65d", "question": "Who said, \"Champagne should be dry, cold, and free\".?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb1", "question": "What philosopher argued for natural rights in his 1651 \"Leviathan\"?", "answer": "Thomas Hobbes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4b6e206d333868d34d6f6", "question": "What was the very first ship sunk in action in World War II?", "answer": "The Athena", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c341", "question": "How many ventricles does the brain have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ec244b8dc25ca9e12ef637", "question": "In which European country would you find the town of Eupen?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e35", "question": "Who is Campbell Scott's mother?", "answer": "Colleen Dewhurst", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8abf201dd7bf43be5e768", "question": "Most of a US penny is made from what type of metal?", "answer": "Zinc", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bb", "question": "In The Simpsons, according to Mr. Burns, who was a man that could get things done?", "answer": "Rommel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba18c874c93a3298b2127", "question": "Of which US state was Jimmy Carter Governor before he became president?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393bd", "question": "What actor played Hunter S. Thompson in the movie \"Where The Buffalo Roam\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010caec0775fa611bce6800", "question": "\"A la Crecy\" is a French cooking term that describes a dish that is made or is garnished with what?", "answer": "Carrots", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c452", "question": "What are there 270 of in the average human baby but only 206 in an adult?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace7", "question": "What country saw the 1979-80 hostage crisis that ended as Ronald Reagan took his oath of office?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddf596ce05a3942286db0", "question": "Which music legend was sentenced to six years in prison in 1988?", "answer": "James Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d7", "question": "Which actor played the role of God in the movie \"Bruce Almighty\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac6", "question": "Playwright Thomas Lanier \"Tennessee\" Williams was born in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a470", "question": "What is the capital of Mali?", "answer": "Bamako", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b441", "question": "Where were the 1960 Summer Olympics held?", "answer": "Rome, Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab47", "question": "Mogadishu is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Somalia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c944", "question": "Who invented the kinetoscope?", "answer": "Louis Le Prince", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a632", "question": "The Niagara Falls empties in which Great Lake?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c33f877e98cb97778993", "question": "Where is the world's first underwater hotel?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c64", "question": "What full feature movie marked Steven Spielberg's directorial debut?", "answer": "Firelight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339834", "question": "What movie won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 1991?", "answer": "Dances With Wolves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600240f84be4723ccac2216d", "question": "In the novel \"Dances with Wolves,\" what name does John Dunbar give to the wolf he befriends?", "answer": "\"Two Socks\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3a", "question": "Whose novel \"Sweet Thursday\" formed the basis for the 1955 Rodgers & Hammerstein musical \"Pipe Dream\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02a", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Franz Gutentag was once what?", "answer": "A Nazi war criminal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f2", "question": "What note is the highest string of a violin usually tuned to?", "answer": "E", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049ae8cf93664eb104869b", "question": "Marvel Comics was acquired by which major media and entertainment company in 2009?", "answer": "The Walt Disney Company", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a6", "question": "What was the name of the restaurant the TV series \"Happy Days\"?", "answer": "Arnolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c934", "question": "The Campbell-Stokes Recorder measures what with a glass ball?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbd", "question": "Who wrote \"Kubla Khan\"?", "answer": "Samuel Taylor Coleridge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339037", "question": "What is non-rhyming poetry called?", "answer": "Blank verse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8b", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Danny in \"City Slickers\"?", "answer": "Jake Gyllenhaal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c96", "question": "In Charles Dickens' \"Oliver Twist\", what is the name of the man who trains boys to steal for him?", "answer": "Fagin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008daa8f4f3bc4a292f8616", "question": "What does the Latin phrase \"Sic semper tyrannis\" mean?", "answer": "\"Thus always to tyrants\" (It is short for \"Sic semper tyrannis ad mortem\", which means \"Thus always I bring death to tyrants\".)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f1683df7c52aae91cc07c4", "question": "What is the fear of light flashes known as?", "answer": "Selaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3de", "question": "What city is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5904987acf93664eb1048687", "question": "What is the name of the base twenty numbering system?", "answer": "Vigesimal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b497", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bed", "question": "What undiagnosed condition forced singer Cher to leave high school at age of 16?", "answer": "Dyslexia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad76", "question": "Whose tomb was found in the Valley of the Kings in Egypt?", "answer": "Tutankhamun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a286", "question": "Which 2008 film starring Seann William Scott features an epic live-action role playing battle in its climax?", "answer": "Role Models", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a254", "question": "What year was Alfred Hitchcock born?", "answer": "1899", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c9", "question": "Who directed the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Henry Koster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b85c", "question": "What does a funambulist do?", "answer": "Walks on tightrope", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339840", "question": "In \"Monty Python And The Holy Grail\", what group demanded that Arthur bring them a shrubbery?", "answer": "The Knights who say Ni", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb84", "question": "How long, in feet, is the Brooklyn Bridge?", "answer": "5,989 ft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7e", "question": "How many red squares are there on a standard checker board?", "answer": "32", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a095", "question": "What was the name of Punky Brewster's dog?", "answer": "Brandon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ad", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Granite State\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e9", "question": "What kind of creature is Mowgli's enemy Shere Khan in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Tiger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ea", "question": "Which is the highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77cf0f24f0f7a362efd54b", "question": "In the first Super Mario Bros. game, in which level is the first three-world secret exit?", "answer": "World 1-2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c7", "question": "Ralph Freeman designed which Australian landmark?", "answer": "Sydney harbour bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee5", "question": "What future \"Grey's Anatomy\" costar played Sandra Oh's lover in the movie \"Under the Tuscan Sun\"?", "answer": "Kate Walsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5ef46ce05a3942286e3c", "question": "Who had a hit song with the theme from the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ray Parker, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c9e", "question": "What Ray Charles song was the basis for Kanye West's \"Gold Digger\"?", "answer": "I Got a Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0f", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"On the Move\"?", "answer": "Mannequin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf1", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest diamond company?", "answer": "De Beers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec25cd8dc25ca9e12ef642", "question": "What fraternity do the Lewis and Gilbert join in the 1984 film \"Revenge of the Nerds\"?", "answer": "Lambda Lambda Lambda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b027", "question": "Who was the 36th US President?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f8b001dd7bf43be5e846", "question": "\"All the news that's fit to print\" is the motto of which newspaper?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a448", "question": "Which country is home to the spring festival called \"Holi\"?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8c", "question": "Goitre is mostly caused by what deficiency?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a754", "question": "Which four US states begin with the word \"New\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico and New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a6", "question": "In what city do The Simpsons live?", "answer": "Springfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1e16682715b82711ce4", "question": "What is the name of the strait located between the Italy and Albania?", "answer": "Straits of Otranto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc33eec223966ae8f887c", "question": "What actor won the inaugural Razzie Redeemer Award by going from a flop (Gigli) to hits (Argo and Gone Girl)?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70b", "question": "How many calories must you burn to lose one pound?", "answer": "3500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e7f1fe83fe1f2a824bd7", "question": "When did the Peasants Revolt take place?", "answer": "1381", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941c", "question": "What was the name of Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c164", "question": "Selaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flashes of light", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a205", "question": "Who is Yogi Bear's sidekick?", "answer": "Boo Boo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc3", "question": "According to the KFC ads, how many herbs and spices are in Colonel's secret recipe?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab9", "question": "The \"Happy Days\" spin\u00adoff, \"Joanie Loves Chachi\", was set in which city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e87", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Opie in \"Andy Griffith\"?", "answer": "Ron Howard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66932a5bfecdd737e0878", "question": "How many days is Ramadan?", "answer": "29 to 30", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bc", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Silver State\"?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd65", "question": "What's sometimes called a \"licking stick\" or a \"tin sandwich\"?", "answer": "A harmonica", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41f", "question": "Who was the first Chancellor of the German Federal Republic?", "answer": "Konrad Adenauer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3db", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath end her life?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c227", "question": "Who claims to have invented the Mai Tai cocktail in 1944?", "answer": "Victor J. Bergeron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394eb", "question": "What is the name of the Green Hornet's car?", "answer": "Black Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e6", "question": "What year was writer Arthur C. Clarke born?", "answer": "1917", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee1", "question": "What position was first held by George Clinton?", "answer": "Governor of New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbfa56ce05a3942286f02", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Black Magic Woman\"?", "answer": "Santana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89f", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the moon?", "answer": "Selenium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e949d7ccba3ffe45786d5", "question": "How many inches is a span?", "answer": "9 inches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9ba81364247bf200fb898", "question": "Which political party was co-founded in West Germany in 1979 by the late Petra Kelly?", "answer": "The Green Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1d", "question": "What was the scarecrow in \"The Wizard of Oz\" lacking?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393da", "question": "The movie \"Heart Like a Wheel\" was a story about which drag racing legend?", "answer": "Shirley Muldowney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c906", "question": "What color is the tip of a Canada lynx's tail?", "answer": "Black", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3de244f0f6af5b066641", "question": "Andorra is part of which continent?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a4ef20565ad31a57c7c4", "question": "Who was the first lawyer to become US President?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339272", "question": "What is the real name of the Food Network's chef \"The Barefoot Contessa\"?", "answer": "Ina Garten", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b187", "question": "Who was US President Ronald Reagan's first wife?", "answer": "Jane Wyman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b017", "question": "What Roman gladiator led a slave revolt that became the subject of a 1960 Oscar \u00adnominated movie?", "answer": "Spartacus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede60a6ce05a3942286df4", "question": "On what avenue does the traditional New York City Easter Parade and Bonnet Festival take place?", "answer": "Fifth Avenue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2d", "question": "What Greek god, killed by a wild boar, inspired Percy Shelley's elegy for his friend Keats?", "answer": "Adonis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81cc8d0de9af39e9d4688", "question": "As of 2020, who was the only president to be awarded the Purple Heart?", "answer": "John F Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59637219967692ea851899bd", "question": "Ford produced the Model T in only what color after 1913?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecce2eec223966ae8f88af", "question": "What movie popularized the phrase: \"Show me the money\"?", "answer": "\"Jerry Maguire\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b019", "question": "Prior to Ronald Reagan, who was the last US president whose first and last name began with the same letter?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c394", "question": "What is crossed with a blackberry and loganberry to produce a boysenberry?", "answer": "Raspberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f95b1b655722f97b22684dd", "question": "What year did the Original Dungeons and Dragons box set by Gary Gygax and Dave Arneson debut?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef631a6ce05a3942286e62", "question": "Who was the first guest on \"Late Night with David Letterman\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32b", "question": "Which character did Eddie Murphy play in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Reggie Hammond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4b36ce05a3942286f35", "question": "Who replaced Curly of the Three Stooges after he had a stroke in 1946?", "answer": "Shemp Howard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eadc3f83302ff91e46480", "question": "How is Alistair Leslie Graham better known as on TV?", "answer": "Ali G", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe768dfeec85e375820b2a8", "question": "Between which two African countries is there a land that no one owns?", "answer": "Egypt and Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8ce4794b094db915830a6", "question": "The city of Acapulco is located in which Mexican state?", "answer": "Guerrero", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cfb6bb53d1af658864f5", "question": "The song \"Jingle Bell Rock\" is performed during the opening credits of which \"Lethal Weapon\" film?", "answer": "The first one", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdaf5ec223966ae8f88ee", "question": "Which film earned Stanley Kubrick a Razzie nomination for Worst Director?", "answer": "\"The Shining\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9a", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Schuss\"?", "answer": "Skiing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339440", "question": "Why is Bob Harris in Tokyo in the movie \"Lost in Translation\"?", "answer": "To film a whiskey commercial", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590089fbcf842fa4c4ba968e", "question": "Which band recorded the album titled \"Slippery When Wet\"?", "answer": "Bon Jovi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899c3c60d398dc9cf7a6a6", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Hestia?", "answer": "Vesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddbe56ce05a3942286d95", "question": "What was the name of the movie that Elvis Presley made his film debut in?", "answer": "\"Love Me Tender\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909d", "question": "Who was the Greek god of harvest and agriculture?", "answer": "Demeter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9bb", "question": "Approximately, how many times larger than Rhode Island is Texas?", "answer": "257", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fe", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Venus?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febaf0d7e83c707845b20fa", "question": "What is the most venomous fish in the world?", "answer": "Reef stonefish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aee", "question": "What was Underdog's secret identity, which was also his occupation?", "answer": "Shoeshine boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6578fae7e414034b5aedd", "question": "Who succeeded Neville Chamberlain as British prime minister in 1940?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a1", "question": "Who played the role of Michael Clayton in the 2007 movie by the same name?", "answer": "George Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c58", "question": "What year did singer Whitney Houston die?", "answer": "2012", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b176", "question": "In what year did the State of California officially join the United States as its 31st state?", "answer": "1850", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890f", "question": "Who wrote \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Robert Louis Stevenson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e90fb89d7247dfc0fa00306", "question": "From the anime \"Fairy Tail\" who is known to be Titania, The Queen of Fairies?", "answer": "Erza Scarlet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81fe5d0de9af39e9d469b", "question": "What year did Amazon.com make its first sale?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea83c7ff048f679a45ac2b", "question": "What is the largest human organ?", "answer": "Skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389ca", "question": "What decade was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" set in?", "answer": "The 1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7da", "question": "What kind of an animal is the \"horny toad\"?", "answer": "A lizard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59029d91cad1ec93f27df74f", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade1", "question": "What year did the Han Dynasty come into power?", "answer": "206 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97f", "question": "What African country calls itself the \"Land of a Thousand Hills\"?", "answer": "Rwanda", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8beeec223966ae8f8845", "question": "The protagonist in \"Grand Theft Auto: Vice City\" was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c127", "question": "Which Jamaican city was Olympic sprinter, Don Quarrie, born in?", "answer": "Kingston", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7db", "question": "What was the first European country to ban smoking in bars?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06c", "question": "During the mid-1800\u2019s, what was the principal cargo aboard Mississippi River Steamboats?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedd8a96ce05a3942286d72", "question": "What is the name of the highly-entertaining main villain of \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Agent Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee0", "question": "What literary villain died during a struggle at Reichenbach Falls?", "answer": "Professor Moriarty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a6", "question": "What European nation still pledges its allegiance to a foreign monarch in its national anthem?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72e", "question": "The Luray Caverns can be found in which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb2", "question": "What provides the red color in a Tequila Sunrise?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a9", "question": "What musical tells the story of a group of young artists struggling to survive in New York?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb71", "question": "In 1992, what city hosted the first World Series game ever played outside the US?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339525", "question": "Who directed the 1927 movie \"Metropolis\"?", "answer": "Fritz Lang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede1b36ce05a3942286dc4", "question": "What is Michael J. Fox's middle name?", "answer": "Andrew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c50efbde8045e48466a6", "question": "What is a phanerogam?", "answer": "Plants that produce seeds -- The most advanced plants on the evolutionary scale, they used to go by the name spermatophytes.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51544ff04d658268c92e9", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "The Wars of the Three Kingdoms, aka British Civil Wars, took place in\u00a0England, Ireland and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade3", "question": "What was Liu Bang, founder of the Han Dynasty, posthumously known as?", "answer": "Emperor Gaozu of Han", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b36f471c3f17ccc40c8e0d", "question": "How many Academy Awards was the film \"The Sixth Sense\" nominated for?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029ed3cad1ec93f27df758", "question": "What is champagne substituted with to turn a \"Black Velvet\" cocktail into a \"Poor Man\u2019s Black Velvet\" cocktail?", "answer": "Cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fb", "question": "Who were the two founders of the company \"Hewlett-Packard\"?", "answer": "Bill Hewlett and Dave Packard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdd", "question": "What is the National Bird of India?", "answer": "The Indian Peacock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d7", "question": "Meg Ryan and Tom Hanks appeared together for the first time in which movie?", "answer": "Joe Versus the Volcano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79f", "question": "Who is credited with the discovery of Neptune's moon, Triton?", "answer": "William Lassell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a67120565ad31a57c7d9", "question": "What is the name of the first nuclear-powered merchant ship?", "answer": "NS Savannah", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c46", "question": "What city's \"Tin Pan Alley\" was known for its music publishing industry?", "answer": "New York", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa74f73838c5c8a417f37", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25af1b63e5727cf5a4857", "question": "The song \"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You\" was the title track to which film?", "answer": "Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32d", "question": "What does TNT stand for?", "answer": "Trinitrotoluene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b993", "question": "What number was retired by the Chicago Bulls to honor Michael Jordan?", "answer": "23", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c82f", "question": "What plant takes its name for the Chinese words for \"man root\"?", "answer": "Ginseng", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdbd1e347d002c297e4e1", "question": "What meteorological significance is traditionally attached to cows lying down?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a7f58b6f5f79087132fb3f", "question": "Which religious figure is depicted in many of the tallest statues on Earth?", "answer": "Buddha", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3c", "question": "What 2003 Samuel L. Jackson/Colin Farrell movie was based on a mid-1970's  TV show?", "answer": "S.W.A.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa52", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritania?", "answer": "Nouakchott", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339596", "question": "Published in 1990 which Michael Crichton novel was made into an Oscar-winning film 3 years later?", "answer": "Jurassic Park", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a724", "question": "What two rivers meet in Nebraska to form the Platte River?", "answer": "North Platte River and South Platte River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d2f6bb53d1af6588650e", "question": "Who played the lead role in the 1983 film \"Merry Christmas, Mr. Lawrence\"?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339584", "question": "Who directed the 1968 movie \"Night of the Living Dead\"?", "answer": "George A. Romero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e0b3e748bb36357acdef", "question": "The FLOW-MATIC programming language, invented by US Rear Admiral Grace Hopper, is the main predecessor to what modern language? ", "answer": "COBOL", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26c", "question": "What kind of natural disaster destroyed three of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World?", "answer": "Earthquakes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afbe", "question": "The first action of which war took place at Lexington?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc9", "question": "Is it true that the Special Sauce on a Big Mac is Thousand Island Dressing?", "answer": "No, it has more ingredients", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a707", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peach State\"?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fc85570abc30a8194e188ad", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa37", "question": "What is the capital of Ethiopia?", "answer": "Addis Ababa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339934", "question": "What US city is mentioned in the first line of the Bob Seger song \"Turn the Page\"?", "answer": "Omaha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a228", "question": "In what year was Puff Daddy's \"I'll Be Missing You\" song released?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3234debf195a31e15d73a9", "question": "Who played Derek Flint in the 1966 film \"Our Man Flint\"?", "answer": "James Coburn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7f", "question": "Who was the losing coach in the first Super Bowl, played January 15, 1967?", "answer": "Hank Stram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989acb0cb8751d53e7d760c", "question": "Which two twin primes add up to 360?", "answer": "179 and 181", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e80679de59ea584496feb1", "question": "Where is the Space Needle?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c43", "question": "Who wrote \"The Cat in the Hat\" and \"Green Eggs and Ham\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339817", "question": "What singer was born Cherilyn Sarkisian?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc22b6ce05a3942286f1a", "question": "The powerful mineral vibranium is mined from which fictional country?", "answer": "Wakanda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16814f7c52aae91cc07c2", "question": "Which opera singer was known as \"La Stupenda\"?", "answer": "Joan Sutherland", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27f", "question": "What is the oldest and most numerous class of animals?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a7fd6c0f9723ab15cb61", "question": "What are the names of the \"see no evil, hear no evil, speak no evil\" monkey statues?", "answer": "Mizaru, Kikazaru, and Iwazaru", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ba", "question": "What does a phobophobe fear?", "answer": "Fear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e1", "question": "P.J. Clapp is better known by what name?", "answer": "Johnny Knoxville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728c666bcd28c119383286", "question": "What year was the first edition of \"The Guinness Book of Records\" published?", "answer": "1955", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b287", "question": "Molotov cocktails were first used by what country after the Soviets invaded it in 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbe4a6ce05a3942286eec", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon\", Francis Dolarhyde is obsessed with the painting of what English poet?", "answer": "William Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e94e17ccba3ffe45786d9", "question": "What language was the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "FLOW-MATIC", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76be9eec85e375820b2ca", "question": "Where is the highest sand dune in Europe?", "answer": "Arcachon, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62a", "question": "What islands were purchased by the US from Denmark in 1916?", "answer": "US Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf2", "question": "What was the official name for the World War II evacuation of Dunkirk?", "answer": "Operation Dynamo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592201b0a4edfd43a087addb", "question": "What is the first name of the fictional character \"Miss Marple\"?", "answer": "Jane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b914", "question": "What popular toy was invented by taking empty pie plates are throwing them in the air?", "answer": "Frisbee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cd", "question": "What type of plane was the B-29 Superfortress?", "answer": "A bomber", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b761", "question": "How tall is a regulation adult soccer goal?", "answer": "8 feet or 2.44 meters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a544", "question": "Which US state is home to Clemson University?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d6f82596a59cbdfbd3b0", "question": "Who invented the lint roller?", "answer": "Nicholas McKay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd201ec223966ae8f88c2", "question": "How many visible cuts are there in the 2014 film \"Birdman\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba3c0874c93a3298b2140", "question": "What was the full name of Queen Elizabeth The Queen Mother", "answer": "Elizabeth Angela Marguerite Bowes-Lyon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe0", "question": "What was the name of Juliet's cousin killed by Benvolio in \"Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Tybalt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef60c26ce05a3942286e4b", "question": "Who won the first Academy Award for Best Actor ever presented?", "answer": "Emil Jannings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afef", "question": "President William McKinley was a member of what political party?", "answer": "Republican Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a975", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The States-General?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea8360ff048f679a45ac27", "question": "What animal is known as \"the unicorn of the sea\"?", "answer": "Narwhal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7d", "question": "What type of shadow portraits are named for a former French finance minister?", "answer": "Silhouettes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab1861baab681b09292189", "question": "The automotive engineering company, Cosworth, is known for its close relationship with which large car manufacturer?", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e147973dd42e4a67cb8d3ee", "question": "What were the 14 haunting paintings Francisco Goya painted in the later years of his life called?", "answer": "The \"Black Paintings\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c4", "question": "What were the colors on the original game of Twister?", "answer": "Red, yellow, blue and green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c96", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Norwich, Vermont?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa4b", "question": "Which country's capital is Belmopan?", "answer": "Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b2bb01dd7bf43be5e7a2", "question": "A group of ferrets is called what?", "answer": "A business", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e72cc9ed0874f1a5e2d1c24", "question": "What is Michael J. Fox\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Andrew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8d", "question": "What bread's name may come from German words meaning \"devil's fart\"?", "answer": "Pumpernickel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c30f", "question": "Theobromine, a substance found in what aphrodisiac, is poisonous to dogs?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a439", "question": "What is the world's smallest country?", "answer": "Vatican City state", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62c", "question": "What US city is nicknamed \"Emerald City\"?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa0", "question": "What is the capital of Niger?", "answer": "Niamey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69d9920565ad31a57c778", "question": "Which national reserve ended in 2015 after the Supreme Court declared it was unconstitutional?", "answer": "National Raisin reserve", "category": "history"}]